Jan **Duchniewicz**

🛮 +48 695 671 937 | 💌 j.duchniewicz@gmail.com | 🏶 www.jduchniewicz.com | 🖸 JDuchniewicz | 🛅 jduchnie

Summary.

I am a student of Embedded Systems Master Degree at KTH Royal Institute of Technology, Stockholm and University of Turku, Finland. My experience ranges from embedded and systems programming, through FPGAs, audio/video processing, game engine development to Machine Learning and DevOps. I am proficient with C++14/17 and C in video/sound processing.

Currently my focus is in the area of embedded Machine Learning, Rust language and Embedded Health applications. Being a team player, I often mentor other people, be it at work or during game jams/hackathons. I often share my knowledge on my personal website via blog posts.

Education

EIT Digital Master School

Europe

M.Sc. IN EMBEDDED SYSTEMS

Sept. 2020 - Present

- Holder of EIT Excellence Scholarship
- · Winner of Digital Health Summer School with "Medpipe" personalized tracker for recovery in endoprosthetic surgeries.

KTH Royal Institute of Technology

Stockholm, Sweden

M.Sc. IN EMBEDDED SYSTEMS

Sept. 2021 - Present

University of Turku

Turku, Finland

M.Sc. IN EMBEDDED SYSTEMS Sept. 2020 - Aug. 2021

Warsaw University Of Technology

Warsaw, Poland

B.Sc. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND NETWORKS

FPGA BASED HARDWARE ACCELERATOR FOR MUSICAL SYNTHESIS FOR LINUX SYSTEM.

Oct. 2016 - Aug. 2020

- Nomination to IEEE Polish Diploma Contest
- Implemented DDS sythesis, filtering and sample accumulation in Verilog in a streamlined fashion.
- Implemented polyphony and various waveform shapes.
- Synchronized the programmable logic with the MCU.
- Deployed the solution in the De0 Nano SoC FPGA.
- Implemented Linux kernel drivers for communication with the FPGA and ALSA subsystem.
- Implemented the ALSA soundcard driver.
- Wrote userspace application for communicating MIDI commands to the FPGA via a kernel driver.
- Tested the solution to ensure smooth and high-fidelity sound.

Experience

TietoEVRY Remote

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Dec. 2021 - Present

· Confidential. 5G related network programming.

Google Summer of Code, beagleboard.org

Remote

EMBEDDED SOFTWARE ENGINEER

May. 2021 - Aug. 2021

- Using OpenGL ES 2.0 and EGL for GPGPU computation accelerations on BeagleBone Black with SGX 5xx GPU's.
- Wrote library in C which makes these computations easier.
- Implemented most popular computations (scalar operators, array operations, 2D convolution).
- Wrote both single-shot and chain API (for combining computations).
- Benchmarked the library on various data sizes.
- · Documented the project on a blog.

Samsung Electronics JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Korea Feb. 2018 - Mar. 2020

- Improved Tizen Operating System Broadcast middleware (C++/C/Arm assembly).
- Managed performance in an embedded system, through code restructurization and thread-wise code improvement.
- Improved performance of code in major broadcasting pipelining module by aware refactorization and smart usage of C++17 STL and Boost library.
- Improved overall health of code, by analysis of coredumps and various system logs. When deemed necessary provided other teams with ready solution.
- Developed from scratch a multithreaded C and C compliant middleware process, with custom threaded work queue implementation.
- Worked with version control tools (git, p4) and in an agile environment (scrum).
- Developed bash and python scripts aiding development and analysis of problems.
- Developed python utility program for automation of defect analysis.
- Traveled to South Korea to aid with defects management during commercialization and to offer quick support.
- · Worked in a diverse multi-cultural environment (directly with a group of 30 people), giving helping hand those who needed it.

Samsung Electronics Warsaw, Poland

INTERN

Supported in project management and knowledge transfer from other R&D Institute.
Based on good performance and analytical skills got an offer for full-time work.

BoSport/Beskid Ski Arena

Chałupy/Szczyrk, Poland

Jun. 2014 - Sep. 2017

Dec. 2017 - Feb. 2018

- KITE/WIND/SKI INSTRUCTOR
 Worked with all kinds of people, teaching them and maintaining good relations througout the years following.
- Taught in various changing conditions, always taking responsibility for life of others.
- Taught in both Polish and English in groups up to 10 people.

Extracurricular Activity

BIBoP Warsaw - Poland

PROGRAMMING AND ELECTRONICS LEAD

Mar. 2021 - Jun. 2021

- Wrote project architecture and data collection from sensors.
- Created a ML model for Blood Pressure predictions from PPG.
- Deployed the model on AWS Lambda with custom hooks.
- Implemented networking over MQTT protocol.
- Soldered and assembled the prototype.
- Designed and soldered analog Galvanometer.

Envidrawer Warsaw - Poland

PROGRAMMING AND ELECTRONICS LEAD

Sept. 2020 - Jan. 2021

- · Designed a sustainable, automated plant growing solution working in varying climate conditions.
- Programmed a sensor-monitoring system and a visualisation web-based service.
- Designed and implemented an analog control ciruit as well as 12 V powering circuit.
- Nurtured friendly atmosphere and healthy work-life balance during the project with 2 other members.

BEYOND 2030 Challenge

MENTOR

Turku - Finland

Oct. 2020 - Nov. 2021

- Guided a group of 2 high-school students in their environmentally sustainable project Smart bee-hive.
- Provided support in technical and project management matters.
- Gave support where needed, pulling the students instead of pushing.

PolyEngine Warsaw - Poland

Developer Oct. 2017 - Present

- Reimplemented Entity Component System systems.
- Refactored code and cleaned architecture of engine.
- Developed various necessary features during gamejams (both gameplay and engine-wise).
- Developed 3 games during Global Game Jam 18/19 and Slavic Game Jam 18.
- Developed efficient data structures for a game engine: string and queue with STL compliance.

KNTG Polygon Warsaw - Poland

Oct. 2017 - Jun. 2019

VICE PRESIDENT AND EVENT ORGANISER

• Organised weekly meetings for student game development group Polygon.

- Gave two talks on Modern C++ usage and easily overlooked nuances.
- Planned and realised two 4-meeting editions of Game Dev Fest: invited lecturers and managed sponsorship of both events.
- Managed sponsorship funds and promotion of both events.
- Helped organise game jams (Polyjam 2018/2019).

Skills_

Programming C++17, C, C#, Rust, ARM/x86 assembly, Python, Bash, LaTeX, Verilog, VHDL, OpenGL ES

Technical FPGA, Electronics, Microcontrollers, RTOS, Linux Kernel, DSP, ROS, CUDA, PyTorch, Deep Learning, DSP, Hardware

Accelerators, GPGPU, Network Stack, IoT, Compilers, Game Engine Architectures

Languages Polish, English, German, Spanish

Honors & Awards

Winner - Best Enterpreneurial Team, EIT Digital Summer Health SChool 2021
 "Medpipe" - an application that will help people managing their treatment timeline and supporting materials (diet, exercises, lifestyle) before and after surgery.
 Honorable mention, Warsaw Film School Game Jam VI
 "Eternal Feud" - Low-poly, competitive co-op, made in a duo team.
 Honorable mention, Static Code Analysis Competition - Samsung Electronics
 Global
 2nd Place Overall, 2nd Place in Innovation, Polyjam, Global Game Jam 2017
 Warsaw, Poland
 "Ommm" - Controlling a monk with the power of your voice.